

 \searrow

adakibet@gmail.com



+254 745 311-001



MOMBASA, Kenya



adakibet.dev



linkedin.com/in/ada-kibet-877338189



github.com/ada-k



medium.com/@adakibet

SKILLS



PyTorch











Adah Kibet

A Data Scientist and Machine Learning Engineer ready for remote work or relocation with experience working in Bio Tech, AI, Ed Tech and Software companies using Python, R and Matlab. I have a keen interest in research and combining it with engineering implementations to develop products and create informative, decisive and sustainable analytical and production workflows.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist

Pivot Bio.

02/2021 - 06/2022

Berkeley, USA. (Remote).

Bio Technology Company. Achievements/Tasks

- Automated detection of pass/fail and harvest time for microbial strains by building a 91% accurate CNN time-series classification model using TensorFlow. Spinned multiple EC2 instances to train the model.
- Conducted Power Analyses to inform experimental designs both for microbial and crop trials.
- Led the Data Engineering team. Main focus: building SQL and Spark ETL pipelines.
- Disqualified the validity of satellite imagery in detecting product effect by bagging mixed effect regressors for 30 trials point data after correcting for spatial auto-correlation using Gaussian Process and Spatial Error models in Python, R and QGIS. Generated field maps using ggplot2.
- Built python libraries to: generate reports on the status of data in the Warehouse and set satellite imagery streaming workflows through automated API calls from Planet Labs and Descartes Labs.
- Designed, prototyped, implemented, evaluated and deployed a Lidar Toolkit app in Flask and Bash.

Machine Learning Researcher

Traits Al.

01/2021 - 08/2021

San Diego, USA (Remote).

Achievements/Tasks

- Researched, built, trained, tested, optimised and deployed the FastSpeech2 Text to Speech Conversational AI model using RNNS and GANS in PyTorch on SDSC Comet GPU clusters.
- Researched, built, trained, tested and optimised the Synthesize Obama Speech to Video model in PyTorch and Scikit Learn on AWS EC2 instances. Used GitHub for collaboration.
- Optimised loss functions through hyperparameters tuning and vocoders change with the aid of a TensorBoard and MFA.

Data Science Intern

10 Academy

06/2020 - 10/2020

Berlin Germany (Remote)

Achievements/Tasks

- Designed, built, tested & deployed (Heroku) a web app that predicts Pharmaceutical Sales across multiple stores & analyses existing data. The Random Forest Regressor model had an MSE of 0.01876.
- Performed change point analysis using Theano and Pymc3 to quantify the impact of the Kenyan government policy interventions to slow the spread of COVID-19 then reported the findings.
- Built a Covid-19 tableau dashboard after creating an ETL pipeline using Spark, S3, SQL & python.
- Quantified the impact of Covid-19 lockdown policies on air quality through time series analysis, sentiment analysis & topic modeling using data scraped from Twitter using NLTK, Spacy & ScikitLearn.

Software Engineering Intern

Swahili Box Hub.

04/2010 - Present

Mombasa, Kenya,

2nd Class Honors, Upper Division.

Achievements/Tasks

□ Designed, built and deployed a Marine ecosystem management web app using Django, JavaScript and PostgreSQL db. Integrated GitHub CI/CD into the development.

PROJECTS

Power Analysis

Biometric Attendance

Sentiment Analysis & Topic Modeling

TDS Blogging

EDUCATION

B.Sc Mathematics and Computer Science.

Technical University of Mombasa.

09/2016 - 02/2021

Kubernetes for Developers PluralSight

2022 - 2022